All right we're back here channel nine alive as...of
...comes down because he's rushing down from his talk...scape I'd like to
point out a couple of things I want to tell you a little bit about schedule and then I also want to talk
about some other cool stuff and maybe even do a demo if I have some time...so the first
thing I want to take a look at is we have a sub reddit for microsoft
...dot com...are front such microsoft underscore build go take a look
im watching it to answer any questions also if you go to ten online
...msdn dot com you'll be able to see the...priority watching it so there is
that and then I want to tell you about the schedule that we have going on and then we'll do a little demo so,
coming up micros images like I said running down we'll ask...about...and some of the stuff
that he's done then we have a little bit about the universal windows
platform that's it one-thirty so stay tuned for that.
And, then we have several coming you might've heard of him
irish drama from the gang of
fourI'm seriously having a little fanned way moment on that is that okay I'm...have a fanned
women because the duties like from the gang of four so yeah, so, if I start sweating and
...watch for that it's going to be fantastic and then after that so,
my good friends talking about...six vb fourteen
...things roslyn they'll be mad toward use in and dusting
...so stay tuned for that we got a slate of really exciting stuff to watch it
make sure you stay...because he's running down I thought I would spend a minute looking at visual studio
code...that I was really excited about when they when they talked about it I thought,
you know, why don't we try to download it and install it live?
And, see how that goes so if you go down here you'll see we have...you go to
code that visual studio dot com you'll see it's in there it is obviously still
and preview the website is beautiful I mean look at this goodness
...it is I'm going to download code for windows.
...hit I'm just going to hit run and hope for the
best so looks like it's pretty fast running security scan.
Here we go everyone cross your fingers
...every go so visual studio code is coming up.
They're getting it started as you guys getting
tingling visual studio code people...
So, as they get things set up I just want to say.
It's pretty fantastic I think as...a company microsoft
...for you to have choice and to build anything that you would like on
any platform so as this gets loading just think about the possibilities of the can applications you can
...already on...or on linux you can totally just use
visual studio code to set this up all right so looks like it's done.
That took that took less time...I thought I mean when it when it goes
for filler time waiting for him this was really.
Really fast...so let's see I haven't played with it so let's
You could make
...files you could take a look at the working files you have folders.
Let's try loading up something here so I'm going to go to my projects
again we're discovering this all together and I'm going to go to my kitties...website I
built the kitties website so images select this folder.
There's my account
...you can see it's all in there there's my home comptroller there's my manage
comptroller it's all pretty pretty cool.
You can see here I'm bloating stuff from blob storage I mean it's pretty exciting that to be able to just
...this up notice I went from literally nothing to having visual studio
code...installing it and
running so-if you want-to see this website it's a pretty cool one.
I'm still moving to redman so my kids got a new cat.
So, I made because, you know,
everyone knows that the internet's for cats right so if you go to kitties dot as
your websites dot net it's still loading up it's warming up you'll see this fabulous
website that I built and I could edit now using visual studio code.
So, how cool is that?
All right so as
you're also watching is that spitting out make sure you have your questions ready
...which is a...some...the things that I saw him talk about one was as a
...as your resource manager this is something I started looking at when I built this little
devil application it's pretty interesting how you can sort of groups stuff together and I'm going to ask
you more about that because I have some questions if you have some questions about that as well also it seems like
you talked a little bit about resource providers and a way to
...all of these things
together so there's a have some questions about that and...vm scale sets
...as your service fabric that seem like an interesting thing as
your service fabric seems like a way of being able to build...of micro services on top of stuff so I'm
...about that and orleans actor model so again if you have
your questions make sure you have them ready for him as he makes his way down.
And, then also on the sub reddit here.
All right.
Let me tell you a little bit more about the schedule for tomorrow
we're pretty excited about that we have grooves.
And, another folk other some other people
asking questions are getting some questions asked by mary jo foley.
then it looks like this is pretty exciting looks like we have a hollow lens session.
...that's pretty cool
that's tomorrow at twelve thirty.
And, then we're...talk more about the windows ten platforms
so exciting stuff I think all right so I think my website is ready.
You know, what we have some time let's do he's coming over is you common?
All...he's coming down.
let me show you a little something about I don't know if...have time to cover this but I built a
...let me do this let me do this demo here because we have some time.
So, I've been doing some explorations on the logic
For the new app service platform.
And, I want to show you something so let me go here
to my server explore and let-me delete some stuff.
Here ...deletes...so here I'm in...your.
And, let me go to my storage.
It's refreshing and what I did is and this is again just to
...because I want to know how the sort of all relates to what marquis talking on how to set these
things up but I have a I should have a here's some data so I'm going
to go ahead and go to my kitties here and delete them?
So, I'm going to...delete here.
show you is something fun so I'm going-to go ahead and load up my website again and
...refresh in this I built literally like in ten minutes or now is like a day, you know,
trying to figure stuff out so notice that this is empty you could take a look at the kitties dot
adder websites dot net if you want to don't take it down people.
So, what I'm going to do something to show you something so I'm going to go to my one drive account?
And, in my in my documents I have this these
kitty so I'm going-to go ahead and take a couple.
...I know not that one and I'm going to
drop it overhear into my kitties folders so copy here.
Although he's ready so as it's going you'll see it come up so call-you ready
...of my friend and then I'll show you I'll show you how
this is bill and then maybe you could tell us a little bit about how this sort of so I'm not very good
deadlocks okay I'm a developer I can help you that so help me, yeah, so,
as a developer what is deadlocks what is
...yes.
It is a agile application...deployment management update
lifecycle so it's kind of like all the stuff that the...still like doing
...will actually traditionally does haven't like doing it has the traditionally grown-up in a world where
developers...they don't do much testing testers tasks.
Customers deploy and operate and service engineers oftentimes are fixing the bugs
while the developers are often the...thing I see in this new world the developers and this is kind of born out of
...cloud service delivery and then agile delivery
...because every companies becoming basically a service company when it comes to application
delivery is the developers are part of that hole and then lifecycle of the
application, yeah, it feels like this speed at which we need to put stuff out requires
developers also think about how am I going to deploy this and how am I going to manage this,
yeah, exactly so there was some interesting things I took some notes during your
talk it just happened like you just...rabbit...got a...yourself havel
...but there was a dog...your...
There was a couple of things and I was showing a demo of some app logics
...that I built that uses logic absent web apps and
...api apps one of the things that I've found is that there's a way to sort of
...things together but it felt very
cumbersome to do it in the portal and I saw you doing some stuff at your talk to sort of
managed a little better technical of about that so what I was showing so
...of my points was in this...ops world where you're taking application and
...you need reproducibility deployments of the application and common most common scenario is I
needed the...my test machine my dub machine
then I need to work on it there and then when it's ready any...production
...might be multiple productions that I'm deploying this thing to there might be different sites that I'm deploying
it to there might be a fail oversight that I'm deploying
...to there might...might be an application which different customers going-to-take and deployed
themselves so I need instead of having a...traditional way that we built...
and mit world...developer world is I kind of build my own glued put
everything together and in the it world especially as I'm creating applications
I'm letting them a create so I start with something that's in place and I
app updates and configuration as you can I go you tweak it some more and,
update a little more and you end up with a system that nobody understands can reproduce?
The what I showed you to helps address this kind of problem is what we call goals
state seeking engines...state thinking engines are tied with templates
...template describes what you want to seeing and the
to couple a couple places I should templates...talk this morning one is an as a resource manager
it's being able to describe it in a template exactly how you want your
clouded application to look up and,
in the context of measure research measure cloud application consists of what we call resource types
resources instances of research types...database of website a virtual...storages
accountsend grid api really whatever you want to be and
described...attempt a parameterized template malik and giving it to
a goals heat-seeking engine I get a couple things of that one is the get efficiency
and I get maintain ability so I can look at the template and I understand what is going to do
...the apps going to look like this...database...the website unit...some code into it here's a
...during parameter so...a text file rights adjacent file
...also because then if something does change you can see what literally
changed by going back...when you commit this that's right
yep and I can take that template that description give it to the as a
resource manager and deficiency I get is instead of me saying okay now I need to deploy the
website wait a minute there's a...any from...database let me go add some code
...the...database let me read the connection string from it let-me plum that
into the website all things that...traditionally had to do with my own blue
eyes specify that in the template connections during comes out
of database goes into website so the as a resource managers the basically the
bus data bus that's really and orchestrate...so, yeah,
it's kind of scary when you're deploying these things and then appeals
very brittle like okay this week this okay thanks okay now...now you're, you're tweaking
...file that's right and it will work the next time every and not only that...tweaking it
I can make modifications and I can give the template updated templates after research manager it looks at
it goes these things didn't change these did let me just go change those things to make it look that way you
want to holistic we're going to...of a thirty second break or maybe six
...get...computer hooked up we'll be right back...statement please.
All right where back and I just want to wrap this little
...kitties example I made a logic...sucked files from one drive-in push it up
...up so what you're telling me is that with this new resource
manager this application that I literally like clicked...typed and did all this stuff and
...work if I want to...it how would I go about doing that using the as resource manager
ok so there's a couple things one you can definitely...manager
like you're doing comparatively so you can build-up your resource group this way one of the things you can do is suck
out the basically the concrete realization of that research group
real as adjacent file which kind of like...built-in designer and then,
you know, what you've got to do at that point is parameterized icy?
But, at least it gives you the structure that you want and what you
...together it works you could just suck out the...and then...now if you deployed again it
would deployed exact same thing with all the exact same settings and storage accounts
and everything else which may or may not work right especially if you already have it running right so you want to parameterized
...that way you can then do the things...about what school so I wanted to move on to something else
...one of the cool things that I started looking at was
darker so for those that don't know about doctor what's the difference
between stocker and like a regular vm?
So, darker is a couple things
it's up packaging format a way to the package up an application and deployed
...called doctor images and there's a doctor hub which is registry where it's a public
...hub you can create public-private ones where you go
...put up these images like something like a boon toboon to the
chronicles their maintaining the master images for that you use
doctor client to go get one of these images take your own create your own images and
...container so it's also it's packaging its image management and it's
also container instantiation and also contained container managements as well I see it
so what news did we talk about today that's exciting dot
...couple...the...is around...containers measure this in the keynote was being able to
deployto using the doctor...
Container to a windows server.
...was actually really,
really cool I mean...the thing is exciting to me is I've always thought
...if I'm wrong...expert that doctor was like...minus.
Right...the lighter-weight and they just how do they actually work so,
...there's two aspects of the isolation that you're shooting for when you talk about these container
...world one of them is environmental isolation so the code that
one's inside the container you want to make sure that it works in your...box in your production
box if you deployed it into an empty vm it would just work if...the only thing in there
because nothing's going to collide with it...it creates a file in a certain place nothing else is going to create
...that place but if you put two copies of that thing in the same
vm they might collide onresources like this so one aspect of that containers a
...is virtualization so
linux has basically name space virtualization built into it through
l ...as well as union file system support which is kind of virtual
...file systems each container gets its own private view of the namespaces around process
aidid's around file
systems when it...a filed a certain place it's only it can see it
...and some other container sitting next to it on the same bm...file
that place well it's getting its own private copy they can't see each other and then there's another aspect to
...is often useful is a resource isolation so I want
to make sure that this container doesn't consume more than x percent of cpu because then...appear with the one next to
it so I can again use things like...groups inside
...to control the resource utilization and that container so you don't have
the problem of what works on my machine
exact many go somewhere else and there's a bunch of...you get a lot of predictability around this
...stuff that I saw that you talked about is that now you can
deploy directly those containers from visual studio that's right so we built in container support
...support into visual studio with doctor client being able to point
...doctor hosts...deploy...to it that's cool any other houses around doctor while the what I
did show also was deploying to windows server container and I thought it'd be interesting to show you inside of
windows server complex do it, yeah, so, I've got here
...host it's verge local virtual machine there's the ip address that are most...I did
doctor ps command shows us...in that house and you can see that...number of these...
these host living on the actually on windows...this is a virtual machine that is launched on this
box this laptop...we can't see the virtual machine it's a headlights virtual machine but that's
...ip address ok so there's a doctor engine which is the
run doctor runtime sitting in that virtual machine and I told darker by setting...
hostess told the doctor command by default go talk to this host so when I do the
doctor ps which is list wma containers is talking to that virtual machine saying a any containers running there and
say no I don't have any okay now what I want to do is launcher container in there and I'm going
to launch it here's this command doctor run...name...container...
...interactive and a base the image
...windows server core so it's going to start with that image so the files that are part of windows server
core are going to be what's visible inside that container...and it's going to launch command as
Command and, that's going to let me interact with it so that combination interaction with command from now
...a second here and have an interactive command prompt which is actually running
inside that container on that virtual machine that's really cool because I mean?
Like if it's this vassar for...when I want-to make sure that will work on every
machine I usually had to stand-up of bm and that...forever because right you stood up and then you
had install the os but now you just couple commands put stuff in there just for just
for testing purposes seems like...fantastic for the
dev test cycle because it's so fast and iterative and you get
...the starting point consistent starting point so I'll demonstrate that by doing
executing scent commands in here like system info.
So, this is showing me information about what's nice is in the
...container and container and now what I can do help but just highlight the
fact that this thing is fully isolated I can delete all the entire
...your scary stuff, yeah, they don't do this
...scary...will break your windows...stuff alert so I've
delete I'm deleting the entire softer branch of...look
machine which is part of the control center configuration for windows we're going to see here in a second
...nothing works
out pretty samoa so much depends on querying configuration out there.
So, if you're really destructive mood one, yeah,
then you just can split up a doctor containers are wreaking havoc exactly if you're if you're mad at
something occupy just wish I could delete all the files...of system info doesn't work anymore
help doesn't work anymore in fact the reads command doesn't even work anymore it's the system is
so broken up when I do is exit because
I had a flag that said blower that container one of...this is all gone if I ran recommend again
...get a pristine system.
That...the same image but what I want to show you is give you a little
look about how this is built on top of windows because there's two things going on right there's virtualization
of the namespaces...virtual file system underneath so.
...you already have one darker.
Our...doctor ps dash a garter.
Rm zero eight.
You know, the cool thing like.
It's not like we're moving files around it's like you're trying to make a file that already exist
...literally containers where you can run stuff and I.
Let's see what yeah, because right now you is your loading of a new doctor instance right
...yep and what happen is you try to make one that already had the same name,
yeah,...remove it...yeah, that was a friend, yeah,
because it doesn't matter and what I'm going to do is already p into that?
And, we'll take a look I've got this internals tools installed in there okay.
you know, it's just nota b c one-two-three...pretty much, yeah, that's what we do...microsoft.
And, this doctor host command.
No, actually.
Looks like your...up the container.
just to show you how compatible these containers on windows are process explore on modified.
And, there is I'm not process explorer seeing a view from inside the container
so these are system processing...system processes that have been virtual
lives inside these container these are different than the actual ones on the outside.
now the problem is that I just lost my doctor post ip address.
Because I'm...connect to the host noun show you the view of that container from outside the container.
And, nine...six to eleven.
You don't have ip addresses memorize...
...so this is going to go in again this is going in that virtual machine now that
containers running at this also...this is internals tools installed and we'll take a quick look.
Container from the outside and you're going to see...interesting things on.
Any normal windows system today you're only in
...cone copy of something like the service control manager
...and there it is that if we scroll down.
Scroll down to the bottom you see this other part the process tree
hong here at the bottom.
And, there's another services...running different session that is a virtual lie services
inside that contain all that's what its own service control manager american launch services...
launch processes inside there I can do interactive log...that's what let-me...p intuit
...log on that's in there that spoke completely isolated and now what's this thing is running
honest of last demo here is to show you is I can look I can modify this
data...the outside because I know-how these things are implemented.
Because there's a bhd underneath that container...all the
rights are going and then simply we just blower that bhd when we blower the container
...give this thing and drive letter so we can interact with it so now you're interacting with the
virtual old semi, yeah,
...space of the container by giving it sort of a drive letter
...that's right and I can do things like so,
this...of its windows...windows directory and...a little hard to see...I can do
...text I'm writing into the container from the outside if I go back
And, look, here inside the container.
This is the container inside view half there's going to be a file that magically appeared there.
From the outside...not wearing long sleeves so there's nothing up
is cmu that's what...a question...about almost at a time but I want
...a couple questions is there a dockers as a service on manager only doctoring...so
darker as a service I'm not sure what exactly refers to you can run documents out of linux
...on top of asherthere's no built-in service that says go to plea here's
...retainers...now I what I did
...the session just a second ago is amazes sphere cluster dc os deploying and
...where you can go use that to deploy containers...is not something
...familiar with other people yes amazes...a company that builds the
...those cluster orchestration okay and management of
...an apache open-source project what that does is you give
...a bunch of clusters and you can register application frameworks with it and then
deploy applications so this application...and then
...us takes care of placing containers on different servers doing resource
allocation and...like the robot that puts...needs
to go that's right all right let's take another question would I be able to use darker with windows
...applications like microsoft dynamics crm I would like to quickly move environments around with testing
...about steps so doctor for...microsoft dynamics crm so,
that we're working on getting figuring out what applications we can put in
there so we're still working through some of the application compatibility details for understanding the
full surface area one of our primer scenarios ecourses sp net five
...another one is sql as well so you'll see...and eye out, you know,
we want to make it is the...riches possible...still...work-in-progress but so
the question is remains to be seen yet for exactly how compatible...is with
...guys somewhat on earlier talking about nano server nano
...different...it jeff what's-his-nameyeah,
it was jeffries...or...as a little bit different...always forget his name
...the page I know right before that's, yeah, the original something an hour so
dockers different the nano server how...I think I understand but how would you
...what...there was an operating
...cool thing it's a strip down operating so basically minimalist operating system
designed for cloud scenarios...don't want user experiences on top you don't want
desktop services in there it's basically just the components you need for running a
clout application and that makes it ideal for this containers a...where
I because you're bringing the application and the frameworks and the services with the container so you deploy
the containers and, you want a very thin lightweight os underneath these things
as cool all right next question from the fawn...how
is application isolation in-service fabric compared to...container isolation when it's over
with brings us to service fabric I want to ask about that what is that and maybe
answers question about how it's different to isolation with contain so service fabric I think
is a micros service platform and meaning a...application platform so
you design defy it lets you create applications the consists of
micros services and service
fabric provides a whole bunch of functionality capabilities that make it very easy to do that I
...beyond just deployment of the micros services different servers kind
of cluster orchestration it does health monitoring it does rolling updates it does
partitioning it does load balancing it does and has a name...I
mean I'm just not even half the kids kind of high-level capabilities I just rattled through there's a
whole bunch more and it also support stateful micros services which if you really want to be efficient
...cloud world, you know, what lots around trips to some external store right
you want to keep the state with the compute and allthere's number of art
kind of hyper skill cloud services built on top of service...because they need that efficiency
and service overtakes care of the state management replication that goes the
...it sounds like a lot more than doctor computerization now containers are great with a
package up micros services so one of the things that we don't have today in-service fabric
is support for doctor...arising your micros service but that's coming
okay who are...about out of time we are...to get some
...this is some really cool snaps a lot of fun things having where can we looks this topic want to find out, yeah, well,
so, there's a bunch of sessions a build so there are going to be recorded and be available right after
there's ones on when the server containers ones on deep diving...service fabric ones on as a resource management
resides...thanks for coming down and run after session we'll take a little break
until the next we'll see...